Guide to the University of Chicago Institute for Nuclear Studies Cyclotron Records 1946-1952
University of Chicago Library
University of Chicago. Institute for Nuclear Studies. Cyclotron. Records
1946-1952
0.5 linear feet (1 box)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Institute for Nuclear Studies Cyclotron Records contains correspondence with the Navy and sub-contractors about the building of the cyclotron, the construction of the Accelerator Building, designs for large electro-nuclear machines, and equipment needed to service the cyclotron. The collection also includes budgets and related materials.
Information on Use
Access
No restrictions.
Historical Note
The Institute for Nuclear Studies Cyclotron Records were collected by Professor Samuel K. Allison. Allison received his Ph.D. from the University of Chicago in 1923, did research at Harvard and the Carnegie Institute before going to the Department of Physics at the University of California. The collection focuses on the 170-inch synchrocyclotron, put into operation at the University of Chicago in March, 1947. The project was supported in part by the Office of Naval Research and the Atomic Energy Commission.
Scope Note
The Institute for Nuclear Studies Cyclotron Records contains correspondence with the Navy and sub-contractors about the building of the cyclotron, the construction of the Accelerator Building, designs for large electro-nuclear machines, and equipment needed to service the cyclotron. The collection also includes budgets and related materials.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Allison, Samuel King, 1900-1965; University of Chicago. Institute for Nuclear Studies; Cyclotrons; Particle acceleration
INVENTORY
- Correspondence and diagrams concerning radiation levels, Eckhart Hall, 1945--1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence concerning restoration of high voltage circuit in Eckhart Hall, 1947--1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence and memoranda on purchase of large cyclotron for the Institute for Nuclear Studies and Institute for Radiology and Biophysics, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, January-June, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, July-December, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, January-February, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, March-May, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, June-December, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Large cyclotron budgets and related materials, 1947--1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Large cyclotron budget, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Large cyclotron budget, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Large cyclotron budget, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Large cyclotron budget, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Large cyclotron budget, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)